<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: big picture | Half Nobody]]></title>
  <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/categories/big-picture/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-01T23:42:15-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://halfnobody.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Half Nobody]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Good Riddance, 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/01/good-riddance/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-01T02:12:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/01/good-riddance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm going to come right out and say it. 2012 was not a great year for me. I got broken up with, I "temporarily" moved back in with my parents, had an anxious breakdown, and got fired due to not accomplishing much of anything for an extended period of time (somewhat due to the breakdown). I made progress on, but ultimately failed to complete, two different independent study courses that were to serve as a proof-of-concept for my ability to go back to school and finish up my degree. I ran out of money, got just involved enough with my ex-girlfriend for her to be able to break up with me twice more, gained 20 pounds, and ran out of money.</p>

<p>When I allow myself to reflect, I find that 2012 provided a couple of silver linings:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>I am physically healthy. (Well, actually, I have a bit of a cold <em>right now</em>, but I expect to make a full recovery.)</p></li>
<li><p>I found a psychologist who seems to actually know what he's doing and care about fixing my mental problems.</p></li>
<li><p>The TV show Breaking Bad was pretty great.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>As the year reached its end and I began to reflect upon the goals that were not accomplished by me in 2012, I realized that I am seriously lacking in nearly every important area of my life and if I don't organize my many goals, I will never achieve them. This realization, followed by a few days of pondering, led to this post (and hopefully many more). I have broken down the areas of my goals into the following outline. This is not a perfect representation, but if I wait until perfection to post, I will never post.</p>

<ul>
<li>Happiness

<ul>
<li>Family

<ul>
<li>Marriage</li>
<li>Current Family</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Career

<ul>
<li>Education</li>
<li>Experience</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Spirituality

<ul>
<li>Study</li>
<li>Prayer</li>
<li>Rendering Service</li>
<li>Regularity</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Fun

<ul>
<li>Car</li>
<li>Sports</li>
<li>Comedy</li>
<li>Music</li>
<li>Friends</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>As you can see, I've broken down my ultimate goal of "Happiness" into four areas. These are things that I know have the capacity to make me happy and need to be balanced somewhat. These areas are further broken down into more specific groups that help me see if activities I take part in are actually contributing to my happiness. The next tier, if I were to model it in its entirety, would consist of dozens, if not hundreds of different goals that could all contribute in some way to my happiness. However, I think the current list I have enables me to take a stab at a few of the goals that might have a more immediate effect. The goals I will attempt to focus on include the following:</p>

<h3>Physical Fitness</h3>

<p>This feels cliche. Who <em>doesn't</em> have a New Year's resolution or goal to be in better shape? I believe that by improving my physical fitness through exercise and consuming healthier food that I can improve my ability to pursue fulfilling relationships that could lead to marriage (family). Being in better shape will also improve my enjoyment of sports (fun) and my confidence to make new friends (fun). This improvement in confidence should also help me gain experience in networking which has great potential to improve my future career prospects. I've yet to hammer out the details of this goal area, but physical fitness will be an emphasis for 2013.</p>

<h3>Making More Money Now</h3>

<p>I am currently in a position where I make very little money. I have a sporadic part-time job that pays most of my (nearly nonexistent) bills, but I often feel trapped by my financial circumstances. This significantly lowers my self esteem and raises my stress as I have a car that is breaking down, a rising monthly health insurance bill, and no safety net for any other emergencies. I also need money to afford to go back to school when I'm ready. Most people in my situation would go and get a full-time job, but I am not mobile (due to working with my therapist) and I'm honestly not sure if I could handle regular deadlines and commitments right now.</p>

<p>This leaves me with the option to pick up side projects and odd jobs to bring in spending cash and ideally help me gain experience for my future career. Most of my short-term "making money" initiatives are actually detrimental to my long-term career potential as it is very difficult to get short part-time work doing complicated programming with no experience and no degree.</p>

<p>OK, so I obviously don't have the whole "making more money now" thing all planned and figured out, but it will help my "fun" and my "education" and my "marriage" prospects and if I can get it to overlap with "career," then that would be great.</p>

<h3>Stay Busy and Useful</h3>

<p>Part of the reason I have trouble making money is that I waste hours and hours a day on most typical days. One symptom of my anxiety disorder is that my brain tries to avoid excitement and discouragement by actively changing the subject to anything more bland and mundane. When I'm working on something and I get excited due to a period of success or (more often) discouraged due to things not working quite how I'd like, I find myself almost automatically navigating to Facebook, Hacker News, or Reddit and wasting a bunch of time. Sometimes I can enter something of a comatose state and not realize that hours have passed since the last time I did anything useful. In my current situation, this is not a detriment to my employer, as I only bill him for successful hours. However, it is something that needs to change if I am to achieve the success I desire in my life.</p>

<p>One strategy for dealing with this symptom (as taught to me by my psychologist) involves setting out blocks of time where I only do one thing. For example, I often have five or ten different useful projects to work on I switch between them frequently and randomly. This can at times make me feel like a super multitasking ninja, but I rarely finish any of the projects. Often I will go to the office for ten hours and find that only one of those hours was productive and the productive hour occurred in sixty one-minute increments scattered throughout the day. If I block out one half an hour at a time and resolve to only work on one project in that half an hour, I will be more productive. I have had some success doing this in the last couple of months, but it is difficult to stick to as it is tedious and goes against my wilder tendencies.</p>

<p>A good metric to help gauge my progress in this area would be to document my useful time every day compared to my wasteful time. Hopefully I will get some nice data as this ratio improves. This is probably the most important thing I can do to improve most of my goal areas.</p>

<h3>Tracking Progress</h3>

<p>I plan to submit a daily report to this blog at the end of the day every day documenting my successes and failures. I have never before been able to maintain a daily journal of any type for longer than a week or two, so it's very possible that a handful of posts on this blog will stand forever as a tribute to me once again failing to follow through with a good idea. Hopefully, however, this blog will provide a record of my progress and be something that I can slap my name on and show to future employers as evidence of my ability to overcome my struggles.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
