<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: daily reports | Half Nobody]]></title>
  <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/categories/daily-reports/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-06T02:00:45-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://halfnobody.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Half Nobody]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report: Day 5]]></title>
    <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/06/report-day-5/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-06T01:53:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/06/report-day-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, today was Saturday, so I don't feel too bad about it being a near-complete loss. I woke up and helped take down the Christmas lights and then I laid in bed all day watching TV and playing Portal 2. I know this is going to sound like laziness to some people, but my anxiety today was debilitating. I already have planned in my head a few versions of white lies to get me out of my next couple social obligations. I never know how to come back from this kind of thing. The only solution seems to be to blow off enough things that the seemingly unbearable load shrinks. I'm actually not really sure if I'm supposed to be able to come back from this type of situation quickly. It seems like most of my therapy has been geared towards prevention. Anyways, I have an appointment with my psychologist for Monday morning at 8 AM which I'm just now realizing I might blow off. This sucks. I know that when I get back from talking to my therapist I always feel better about things, but I just can't imagine myself feeling good enough to go see him Monday morning. Complicating things is the fact that I almost certainly will not be awake at 8 AM on Monday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report: Day 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/04/report-day-4/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-04T21:32:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/04/report-day-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wow. Today was bad. I let the little things slide to the point where I had a fairly bad anxiety attack. I felt drawn to self-destructive behaviors. I wanted to drive WAY too fast and eat unhealthy food past the point of being full. I wanted to lay in bed and watch TV and play video games and surf the internet to try to stuff my mind with so much content that I would be able to forget about what a failure I've been.</p>

<p>The thing about feeling like this is I think I would be totally fine if I could just do everything in my life perfectly. If I could make every decision correctly the first time, I would never be awkward and I would never feel anxious. I could be confident and self-assured and 100% positive that I had done everything I could in exactly the right way. Being imperfect, however, means that I rethink and second-guess all my good decisions and my bad decisions devastate me.</p>

<p>Anyways, I found a free personal time punch clock program that should allow me to keep track of my time and help me be more productive. I was actually surprised that there wasn't a better solution out there. I would be interested in a clean program with a nice interface (think github for windows) that would not only keep track of my time to various projects, but block certain time-wasters (facebook, reddit, um... iwastesomuchtime... etc.) while I'm "on the clock." I might look into writing this sort of thing myself, but I need to focus on paying projects right now.</p>

<p>The day wasn't a total loss, however. I came home from work to a nice dinner and Raiders of the Lost Ark on TV. Karen Allen is in all probability my long-lost, time-shifted soul mate. Once I invent time travel, I will save young her from her tedious and boring Hollywood life and introduce her to the glamour of being a programmer's wife. Temple of Doom is on now. That's a bit of a drag.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report: Day 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/04/report-day-3/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-04T00:13:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/04/report-day-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was an OK day. I got to work a little late, but I immediately completed my Project01 task in about ten minutes. I then wasted a few hours before having a quality afternoon working on Project02. I probably had four hours of effective work in about seven hours at the office. I was hoping to find some productivity software that would allow me to clock in and clock out and formalize the accounting of my time. I never got around to it, so I will have to do that tomorrow.</p>

<p>I also looked on Craigslist and applied for other "gigs" in town. I'm hoping to pick up some more temporary work that will enable me to make a few dollars and gain some experience with different types of projects. At the very least, I'll get better at applying for jobs and meeting new people, which is something I should be better at than I am.</p>

<p>This evening I played basketball for a couple hours which was nice. My current weight makes it quite hard on my legs and knees, but I have to start somewhere. It was a bit rough because I still have a bit of a cold, but I was able to get up and down the court OK.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report: Day 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/02/report-day-2/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-02T21:36:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/02/report-day-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm not going to put my weight in the individual reports anymore as it is much easier to input and use if I put them in a spreadsheet. You can find this under the <a href="http://halfnobody.github.com/goals">Goals tab</a> above.</p>

<p>Today was an OK first day back at work. My boss had no work for me today, so all of my time was self-directed time. I spent a good chunk of the morning working on tasks for Project01, but I was working in a task-based manner instead of a time-based manner, which wasn't ideal. I accomplished the tasks without losing too much focus. In the afternoon, I did SEO and Adwords research for Project02 and I learned some interesting things about SEO from chapter 4 of the seomoz beginner's guide. I did this in a time-based manner, but it was quite difficult and I didn't stop at the time that I had decided to stop. This time-based task completion is much easier said than done.</p>

<p>All in all, I probably had about three hours of effective time in the six or so hours I was at the office. Tomorrow I will look for some kind of productivity widget that will allow me to clock in and clock out to more successfully measure my productive time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report: Day 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/01/report-day-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-01T22:44:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/01/report-day-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>Weight: 235.2</h4>

<p>I didn't accomplish much today. I have a bit of a cold and I had the day off. I got this blog up and running and I helped take down Christmas decorations, but other than that, I just stayed in bed reading things on the internet and watching TV all day. I also did a fair amount of thinking about my goals which I will write about in another post. That is all.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
