<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: daily reports | Half Nobody]]></title>
  <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/categories/daily-reports/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-13T05:30:49-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://halfnobody.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Half Nobody]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report: Day 12: No more reports]]></title>
    <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/13/report-day-12-no-more-reports/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-13T04:49:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/13/report-day-12-no-more-reports</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, here's the update... things have not been going well. I've basically spent a week in bed accomplishing almost nothing. This prospective freelance projects where I might get paid if things go well aren't getting me out of bed. I stay awake until I fall asleep from exhaustion (sometime around five or six in the morning) and then I wake up when one of my parents gets sick of me sleeping all day (sometime around noon or two in the afternoon). In the last week I beat Portal and Portal 2 and watched four seasons of a television show. I feel terrible all the time.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Right now I need a job. I need structure. I need a place to go everyday and a time that I have to be there and something to accomplish and someone to check on me to make sure I'm accomplishing something. Also, getting paid would be nice. The main problem is that there's currently no jobs that I'm "qualified" to fulfill. Here's a breakdown:</p>

<h4>Why I should be employable</h4>

<ul>
<li>I know the basics of many programming languages and technologies from low level embedded systems work up to web development and I'm pretty good at a couple of them.</li>
<li>I am a dynamite IT guy with proven experience pulling cables and lots of personal time spent fixing computers and setting up networks.</li>
<li>I am easily in the top 2% of the quickest learners I've ever met.</li>
<li>I am an intelligent, clean-cut, well spoken, white male. Seriously, isn't getting a job supposed to be easy for me?</li>
</ul>


<h4>Why nobody wants to employ me</h4>

<ul>
<li>I have no degrees or certificates.</li>
<li>I've never had a programming job or completed a large enough programming project to prove to anyone that I can do it.</li>
<li>I am <em>very</em> bad at networking.</li>
</ul>


<p>An ideal situation for me would be some kind of internship or apprenticeship where I would work on a team and be able to learn on the job. I would even be willing to work for a lower salary until I'm up to speed as my expenses are very low right now. Anyways, I'm starting to seriously look at jobs that are completely outside the computing world, but at least they'll give me a paycheck and a place to be.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report: Day 7]]></title>
    <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/08/report-day-7/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-08T03:06:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/08/report-day-7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, this reporting thing isn't really working. Today sucked again. I got up on time to make it to my appointment a little bit late. I mentioned this blog and my psychologist didn't think that it was necessarily a good idea. He made a good point about me creating the blog out of a need to feel in control of something which is not a motivation that leads to any sort of lasting change. I can think of some other reasons to keep it going, but I definitely can't just sit around waiting for something to fix me. Anyways, it's very possible that this blog will be taken offline after nine or ten posts only having been seen by me. I think it more likely that I will edit some of the existing posts and then post less often and only when I have something to say.</p>

<h4>Reasons to keep this blog going</h4>

<ul>
<li>Reporting daily gives me a level of accountability.</li>
<li>I suck at consistently doing certain daily tasks.</li>
<li>The daily posts without worrying about being perfect have the potential to improve my abilities as a writer.</li>
<li>I think the daily data collection is useful for tracking certain things and I don't think I will keep it up if I'm not posting it online.</li>
</ul>


<p>I think it's possible that my psychologist would have seen the blog differently if I had presented it more as a daily journal and less as a means of publicly publishing personal information. Anyways, I'll keep thinking on it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report: Day 6]]></title>
    <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/07/report-day-6/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-07T00:20:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/07/report-day-6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, this was my least effective day yet, but I don't feel too bad about it. It was Sunday which is a day I typically earmark for rest and getting my mind off of the work/study/etc. of the week. However, I <em>did</em> pretend to be sick to get out of social obligations. I've been getting over a cold, but it wasn't nearly bad enough. My anxiety, however was at the point where the only thing that could relieve it was deciding not to do things. Also, I slept in past noon which is probably going to have repercussions on this next week especially as I try to make it to my appointment with my psychologist in seven hours. I took some NyQuil to help me sleep earlier, but There's definitely no guarantee that I will fall asleep soon or wake up at a normal time.</p>

<p>I'm starting to think more and more that I need more structure and I should try to get a full-time job. I have more to say about this, but I don't really want to think about it now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report: Day 5]]></title>
    <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/06/report-day-5/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-06T01:53:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/06/report-day-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, today was Saturday, so I don't feel too bad about it being a near-complete loss. I woke up and helped take down the Christmas lights and then I laid in bed all day watching TV and playing Portal 2. I know this is going to sound like laziness to some people, but my anxiety today was debilitating. I already have planned in my head a few versions of white lies to get me out of my next couple social obligations. I never know how to come back from this kind of thing. The only solution seems to be to blow off enough things that the seemingly unbearable load shrinks. I'm actually not really sure if I'm supposed to be able to come back from this type of situation quickly. It seems like most of my therapy has been geared towards prevention. Anyways, I have an appointment with my psychologist for Monday morning at 8 AM which I'm just now realizing I might blow off. This sucks. I know that when I get back from talking to my therapist I always feel better about things, but I just can't imagine myself feeling good enough to go see him Monday morning. Complicating things is the fact that I almost certainly will not be awake at 8 AM on Monday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report: Day 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/04/report-day-4/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-04T21:32:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://halfnobody.github.com/blog/2013/01/04/report-day-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wow. Today was bad. I let the little things slide to the point where I had a fairly bad anxiety attack. I felt drawn to self-destructive behaviors. I wanted to drive WAY too fast and eat unhealthy food past the point of being full. I wanted to lay in bed and watch TV and play video games and surf the internet to try to stuff my mind with so much content that I would be able to forget about what a failure I've been.</p>

<p>The thing about feeling like this is I think I would be totally fine if I could just do everything in my life perfectly. If I could make every decision correctly the first time, I would never be awkward and I would never feel anxious. I could be confident and self-assured and 100% positive that I had done everything I could in exactly the right way. Being imperfect, however, means that I rethink and second-guess all my good decisions and my bad decisions devastate me.</p>

<p>Anyways, I found a free personal time punch clock program that should allow me to keep track of my time and help me be more productive. I was actually surprised that there wasn't a better solution out there. I would be interested in a clean program with a nice interface (think github for windows) that would not only keep track of my time to various projects, but block certain time-wasters (facebook, reddit, um... iwastesomuchtime... etc.) while I'm "on the clock." I might look into writing this sort of thing myself, but I need to focus on paying projects right now.</p>

<p>The day wasn't a total loss, however. I came home from work to a nice dinner and Raiders of the Lost Ark on TV. Karen Allen is in all probability my long-lost, time-shifted soul mate. Once I invent time travel, I will save young her from her tedious and boring Hollywood life and introduce her to the glamour of being a programmer's wife. Temple of Doom is on now. That's a bit of a drag.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
